<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks/Presentations on Population Health Data Science (PHDS) - I </title>
    <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks/Presentations on Population Health Data Science (PHDS) - I </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptively stacked ensembles for influenza forecasting with incomplete data</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019sdss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019sdss/</guid>
      <description>Seasonal Influenza infects an average 30 million people in the United States every year, overburdening hospitals during weeks of peak incidence.Named by the CDC as an important tool to fight the damaging effects of these epidemics, accurate forecasts of influenza and influenza like illness (ILI) forewarn public health officials about when, and where, seasonal influenza outbreaks will hit hardest.
Ensemble forecasts have shown positive results in forecasting 1 to 4 week ahead ILI percentages better than any single model in an ensemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptively stacked ensembles for influenza forecasting with incomplete data</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019adaptivemidas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019adaptivemidas/</guid>
      <description>Influenza prediction can better prepare public health officials for seasonal outbreaks. We propose an adaptive multi-model ensemble forecast method that changes model weights week-by-week throughout the flu season. Without historical training data or when models do not have a track-record, an adaptive model can enhance the public health impact of ensemble forecasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptively stacked ensembles for influenza forecasting with incomplete data</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019adaptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2019adaptive/</guid>
      <description>Seasonal Influenza infects an average 30 million people in the United States every year, overburdening hospitals during weeks of peak incidence. Named by the CDC as an important tool to fight the damaging effects of these epidemics, accurate forecasts of influenza and influenza like illness (ILI) forewarn public health officials about when, and where, seasonal influenza outbreaks will hit hardest.
Ensemble forecasts have shown positive results in forecasting 1 to 4 week ahead ILI percentages better than any single model in an ensemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical trial design in context (discussant)</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2018tct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2018tct/</guid>
      <description>Moderators: Peter Juni, Robert W. Yeh
Discussants: John A. Bittl, Eugene H. Blackstone, Schuyler Jones, Thomas C. McAndrew, Roxana Mehran, Stuart J. Pocock, Matthew T. Roe
3:50 PM How to Make Trials Larger Simpler and Less Expensive Lecturers: Matthew T. Roe
4:00 PM Most Frequent Errors I See in the Analysis and Interpretation of Trials Lecturers: Peter Juni
4:10_PM Non Inferiority Trials Gone Wrong: Examples From the Recent Literature Lecturers: David J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assimilated LVEF: Combining human intuition with machine measurements for sharper estimates of left ventricular ejection fraction</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2018assimilated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2018assimilated/</guid>
      <description>Background: Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) is the most commonly used clinical measure of systolic function and is a powerful predictor of outcomes. Current guidelines recommend using the biplane method of discs (MOD) (modified Simpson’s rule) to measure LVEF however the accuracy of this measurement is dependent on endocardial border detection and orthogonal, on-axis biplane imaging, and studies report both inter and intraobserver variability.
Objectives: In this analysis, we sought to reduce measurement error by fusing the cardiologist&amp;rsquo;s visual approximation of LVEF with the biplane MOD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on interpreting evidence: The p-value and beyond (discussant)</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2017tct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2017tct/</guid>
      <description>Spotlight on Interpreting Evidence: The P-value and Beyond 2:45 PM - 3:30 PM Moderators: Eugene H. Blackstone, Stuart J. Pocock
Discussants: Donald Cutlip, A. Michael Lincoff, Thomas C. McAndrew, Jan G. P. Tijssen, Marco Valgimigli, Roseann M White
2:45 PM Proper and Improper Interpretations of the P-value Eugene H. Blackstone
2:55 PM Beyond Time-to-First Event: Counting Multiple Events, Hierarchical Measures, and Weighted Composites Jan G. P. Tijssen
3:05 PM Alternatives to Traditional P-value Testing: Bayesian Designs Roseann M White</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical trial design, Statistics, and Interpretations (discussant)</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016clinicaltrialdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016clinicaltrialdesign/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection from physical correlations (talk)</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016cnls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016cnls/</guid>
      <description>Cyber-physical systems are critical infrastructures that are crucial both to the reliable delivery of resources such as energy, and to the stable functioning of automatic and control architectures. These systems are composed of interdependent physical, control and communications networks described by disparate mathematical models creating scientific challenges that go well beyond the modeling and analysis of the individual networks. A key challenge in cyber-physical defense is a fast online detection and localization of faults and intrusions without prior knowledge of the failure type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we write about when we write about causality</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016whatwe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2016whatwe/</guid>
      <description>Identifying and communicating relationships between causes and effects is important for understanding our world, but is affected by language structure, cognitive and emotional biases, and the properties of the communication medium. Despite the increasing importance of social media, much remains unknown about causal statements made online. To study real-world causal attribution, we extract a large-scale corpus of causal statements made on the Twitter social network platform as well as a comparable random control corpus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Percolation on Spatial Networks</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015percolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015percolation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooblexity: Demonstration of non-newtonian fluids</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015ooblex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015ooblex/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robustess of Spatial Micronetworks</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015complenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2015complenet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Functional Robustness in Networks</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2014sfinetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/classes/2020F_PHDS1/public/talk/2014sfinetwork/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>