<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>natural language processing | tommcandrew</title>
    <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://thomasmcandrew.com/tag/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>natural language processing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://thomasmcandrew.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>natural language processing</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we write about when we write about causality</title>
      <link>https://thomasmcandrew.com/talk/what-we-write-about-when-we-write-about-causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thomasmcandrew.com/talk/what-we-write-about-when-we-write-about-causality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identifying and communicating relationships between causes and effects is important for understanding our
world, but is affected by language structure, cognitive and
emotional biases, and the properties of the communication
medium. Despite the increasing importance of social media,
much remains unknown about causal statements made online.
To study real-world causal attribution, we extract a large-scale
corpus of causal statements made on the Twitter social network
platform as well as a comparable random control corpus. We
compare causal and control statements using statistical language
and sentiment analysis tools. We find that causal statements
have a number of significant lexical and grammatical differences
compared with controls and tend to be more negative in sentiment
than controls. Causal statements made online tend to focus on
news and current events, medicine and health, or interpersonal
relationships, as shown by topic models. By quantifying the
features and potential biases of causality communication, this
study improves our understanding of the accuracy of information
and opinions found online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
